<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FMSCode</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</description>
    <link>http://fmscode.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://fmscode.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2014 08:10:57 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2014 08:10:57 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Coords</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/coords.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Coords&quot; /&gt;
After months of learning as much as I could find about Mac development, I have finally released my first Mac app, Coords. I had this idea over four years ago when one of the iOS apps I was working on required me to work a lot with map related data. While there were many online tools for converting longitude and longitude to decimal degrees and allowed me to easily find locations, I never felt that these tools were complete enough for everyday use. Initially I wrote an iPad app that allowed me to easily add pins to a map, view their coordinates, and easily save pins for later viewing. While the app worked for me, it was nowhere near a shipping app and eventually I shelved the app. As with most of my shelved ideas, I always kept it in the back of my mind in hope to return to it in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t until June of this year that I started to rewrite the app with the goal of shipping it by the end of the year. The biggest change I wanted to make was changing the app from an iOS app to a Mac app. Coords was the perfect opportunity to learn Mac development since I already knew how the app should work, due to my four year old prototype, and I had an understanding of all the technologies that the app would require. Over the next few months I learned some basic Mac development, got the app working, and then spent the rest of the time rewriting and improving the codebase as I learned new things about Mac development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m extremely happy with the app’s initial release and everything I’ve learned along the way. I’m already working on the next version, and can’t wait to create more Mac apps in the future. I also plan on collecting all the Mac development resources I used to create this app in a future post since specific Mac development, especially AppKit, are hard to find. You can download Coords &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/coords/id927953579?ls=1&amp;amp;mt=12&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/coords/id927953579?ls=1&amp;amp;mt=12&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/mac_appstore.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Coords App Store&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2014 07:42:30 -0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://fmscode.com/2014/11/11/Coords.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fmscode.com/2014/11/11/Coords.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>153811</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Just found a great &lt;a href=&quot;http://allara.blogspot.co.uk/2010/12/total-line-count-for-your-xcode-project.html&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; about totaling lines of code in Xcode Projects. You can easily modify the command to support .swift files to give you an idea of how much smaller your Swift project is as compared to Objective-C. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://allara.blogspot.co.uk/2010/12/total-line-count-for-your-xcode-project.html&quot;&gt;Original Post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;find . -name &quot;*.swift&quot; -print0 | xargs -0 wc -l // Must be used when you are in your project&#39;s source directory
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2014 15:38:11 -0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://fmscode.com/2014/11/02/153811.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fmscode.com/2014/11/02/153811.html</guid>
        
        <category>micropost</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>112008</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With all the Marvel movie news this week, if you want to read the comics that inspired the movies check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://marvel.com/comics/unlimited/home&quot;&gt;Marvel Unlimited&lt;/a&gt;. They offer a ton of digital comics from their back catalog as well as many comics that cover the new movie storylines such as Age of Ultron and Civil War.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2014 11:20:08 -0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://fmscode.com/2014/11/02/112008.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fmscode.com/2014/11/02/112008.html</guid>
        
        <category>micropost</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>180416</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After working with Swift for an entire day I still miss Objective-C, but I’m looking forward to the future with Swift.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 18:04:16 -0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://fmscode.com/2014/10/20/180416.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fmscode.com/2014/10/20/180416.html</guid>
        
        <category>micropost</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>162750</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Probably late to the party, but just found out that MKMapView supports a tint color!
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/162750-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2014 16:27:50 -0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://fmscode.com/2014/10/11/162750.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fmscode.com/2014/10/11/162750.html</guid>
        
        <category>micropost</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>155717</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The new iPhone 6 Touch ID is so much more accurate than the iPhone 5s. Really seems seamless now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2014 15:57:17 -0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://fmscode.com/2014/09/29/155717.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fmscode.com/2014/09/29/155717.html</guid>
        
        <category>micropost</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Controlling My Content</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently switched my personal site from being hosted at Squarespace to a Jekyll/GitHub Pages hosting. I’ve been thinking about doing this for a while due to a few things that nagged me about Squarespace’s setup and editing functionality. Even though I’m no longer using Squarespace I would definitely recommend their service to anyone who wants an easy site with little to no maintenance. While the ease and simplicity of Squarespace is extremely helpful to some, for the kinds of things I want to do with my site in the future Squarespace wasn’t going to cut it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another big reason for the change was due to some recent posts written by Brent Simmons and Manton Reece about controlling your content and being able to move it around at will. This is not really possible with a service like Squarespace where they don’t allow you to easily export all of your content. Lastly, even though Squarespace is doing very well now, and will probably continue to do well, what will happen when they eventually close down or are bought out by a company that could change things for the worse?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going into this change I knew there were a few things I wanted my new site to do better than Squarespace:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Easy setup so I could focus on the content.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Full Markdown support, while Squarespace has Markdown support it doesn’t work well.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The ability to run the site locally to test changes and preview posts.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The option to move the site from host to host with little to no changes to my content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After researching possible site generators I settled on Jekyll.  I’ve always been a fan of Jekyll and have wanted to use it for a while but never found a project to use it on. A big reason I chose Jekyll was the various options I had for hosting the site. You can do everything from copying the generated HTML folder to a server, to the more advanced automatic deployment with GitHub Hooks. For hosting the site I chose GitHub Pages since it is very simple to setup and it allows me to become more familiar with Jekyll without having to worry about the server side of things. And if GitHub was to discontinue their Pages service in the future, I would have plenty of options in hosting and it will be an easy move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This change has really made me want to work more on my site and I can’t wait to learn more about everything Jekyll can do. I plan on writing about my Jekyll setup and some of the things I learned from switching my site in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 14:39:56 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fmscode.com/2014/09/21/Controlling-My-Content.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fmscode.com/2014/09/21/Controlling-My-Content.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Digitally Downloaded Games</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With the release of the new generation of game consoles I adopted a new policy to only digitally download games instead of buying physical discs. I’ve never been a fan of physical media and hated having to go to a store and purchase game. Video Games are the most painful to buy in store because every GameStop I went to had two things in common. First are little kids whining to their parents to buy them a $60 game and the constant harassing to pre-order a game or buy some add-on for something I don’t care about. To not deal with this I have only purchased games for my Xbox One digitally. At first it was great and made me more willing to buy games since I didn’t need to go to a store and deal with the in-store environment. This allowed me to essential hide my Xbox from my TV area since I don’t have to put discs in when I want to play a game, which is a small and lazy thing but something I like. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This all changed with the release of Destiny. I played Destiny during the beta period and loved it, so when the game was released early last week I purchased the game and season pass for $98. It was great because the game pre-downloaded to my Xbox and was ready to play right away. After playing for a couple of hours I quickly changed my mind about Destiny and found the game very repetitive and lacking of a good storyline. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue is that I can’t return the game or trade the game in to help recoup the initial cost. And I fully understood this going into only buying digital downloads, but there should be some kind of system to help reduce the price of digital downloads. The best solution right now seems to be what EA is trying out with a subscription based service for games, similar to Netflix with their streaming service. I think going forward digital streaming services for games will become much more requested and used since it is a good balance of digital games and the ability to reduce the price of video games. To make this work though the game publishers will probably have to take a pricing hit since most new games are around $60 and the subscription service will have to be below that for there to be any hope of success in these new subscription services.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 02:20:59 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fmscode.com/2014/09/19/Digitally-Downloaded-Games.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fmscode.com/2014/09/19/Digitally-Downloaded-Games.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Swift-2 Months Later</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The first language I had ever written any code in was Objective-C. I taught myself everything about Objective-C that I could find in online tutorials, books, and Apple documentation. Being my first language, I thought Objective-C was the best language and nothing would come close to it. Even after I expanded out and taught myself PHP, Ruby, and JavaScript I always thought Objective-C was the most well rounded and complete language. I was also writing Objective-C when there was no such thing as ARC and you had to manually manage your memory. Even with its shortcomings, I loved Objective-C and everything you could do with it and how easy it was for me to pick up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Swift was announced in June at WWDC I was not as excited as others were about a new programming language. Throughout my four years of Objective-C development I had never come across anything that I would have blamed Objective-C for, most of my blame went to the Cocoa/Cocoa Touch APIs. While I had little excitement for Swift, I did download the &lt;em&gt;The Swift Programming Language&lt;/em&gt; iBook and started to play around with Swift in Xcode Playgrounds. And while there were plenty of shortcuts to make things “easier” to write, nothing stood out to the point where I wanted to drop everything and start writing Swift only. I also wasn’t getting excited since Apple said they would be changing the syntax based on developer feedback, which was great for the language and really helped it grow in the past two months. The last thing that held me back was I wanted to write an App that used some of the new Extension functionality of iOS 8 and Yosemite, but every time a issue/bug came up it was difficult to figure out if it was a Swift language issue, beta OS limitation, or me writing buggy code. After a few weeks I decided to put Swift aside and continue to write Objective-C code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t until a week ago that I had some free time and re-downloaded the &lt;em&gt;The Swift Programming Language&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Using Swift with Cocoa and Objective-C&lt;/em&gt; iBook along with the latest Xcode. This time when I used Swift I quickly found myself loving the shortcuts and the various improvements it has over Objective-C and found myself wanting to convert some of my projects over to Swift. I’ve even had issues going back to Objective-C for work projects since I would try to write Swift code and it would cause errors, mainly me not adding a semicolon. Over the past two months Swift has matured and I can’t wait to see how it grows over its life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fmscode.com/2014/08/23/Swift-2-Months.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fmscode.com/2014/08/23/Swift-2-Months.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pinball Map</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;3 Months, 197 commits, 13061 additions and 17107 deletions. These are the pull request statistics for Pinball Map, an app I have been working on for the past 3 months with two other developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This app represented a lot of firsts for me as a developer. My first time working with other developers/designers, who were great during the entire development process, that I did not know from my current job. First time contributing to a Rails app to help build the public &lt;a href=&quot;http://pinballmap.com/api/v1/docs&quot;&gt;Pinball Map API&lt;/a&gt; that powers the app. First time I had a formal set of testers and proper beta releases, actually 6 beta releases to be exact. Overall it was a great experience and can’t wait to ship the next version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app is available in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/portland-pinball-map/id359275713?mt=8&quot;&gt;App Store&lt;/a&gt; and a gallery of screenshots are below.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://fmscode.com/2014/08/13/Pinball-Map.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://fmscode.com/2014/08/13/Pinball-Map.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
